CHARLES CURT

321.831.6888 ♦ Curt.Charles.EE@gmail.com ♦ San Jose, CA

Software, Electrical and Manufacturing Engineer

Quick Overview

I can bring value to any team with a great passion and a deeply curious nature. I've worked as a manufacturing engineer, electrical engineer and now as a software engineer. I've also come to learn through experience that I have a great skill in observation, often overlooked, I can pinpoint tough problems which has on multiple occasions helped the team.

Primary Skills

C Firmware, Electronics Design, Website Design (HTML CSS PHP Javascript), Physics, PCB Manufacturing, EE Test Equipment Python, Linux

Education

Bachelor of Science, Electrical Engineering, Florida Institute of Technology, Melbourne, FL

2017

Experience

Software Engineer

NeurostimOAB

Jul 2018 - Oct 2018

- Programmed IOT low energy BLE device on Qualcomm microprocessor
- Automated software test design created automated tests for software verification
- Low power design principles Learned how to design low power software
- Hardware Testing I found through testing a major bug which improved our design
- Documentation Design Created doc control for all aspects of my design and Git source control
- Intro to Altium helped engineers debug simple Altium issues

Electrical Engineer

Leaf Suit

Mar 2018 – Jul 2018

- Designed startup's electronics design Involved motor, power supply, sensors and software
- Hardware and software testing using EE test equipment verified operation of device
- Using EagleCad, created layout of project designed single layer PCB for prototype
- Marketing, Research and Networking learned how to target a market and talk to investors
- Researcher and Designer

Optronics Laboratory

May 2016 – May 2017

- Published and lead a optics research project into free space optical receiver
- Designed receiver and transmitter for laser communications
- Hardware testing with optical and EE equipment
- Research principles this is what taught me to be very observant (ask me about this)
- Process engineer

Mack Technologies

June 2017 - Dec 2017

- Improved Wave soldering programs by reducing time and strain on board
- Found Underlying issues with inline wash and processes saving money and time
- Discovered circuit failure modes and facilitated improvements needed
- Trained and produced new procedures for operators
- Developed new factory layout using AutoCad from work flow analysis

Test engineer

Mack Technologies

May 2017 - Jun 2017

- Programmed SPEA flying probe and learned circuit and machine failure modes
 - Discovered failure of ICT test equipment, repaired ICT, programmed ICT
 - Diagnosed and fixed test fixtures individually and with test engineers
 - Debug circuit analysis individually and with senior debug team